William N. Fenton Papers 1933-2000 Mss.Ms.Coll.20
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1897-1994; 39 boxes; 19.25 linear feet
  - Weinman, Paul L., 1968 (Box Series I-38)
  - Weir, Frank A., 1988 (Box Series I-38)
  - Weisman, Abner I. (Box Series I-38)
    -See Ser. I, Marshall, Alton G.
  - Wellesley College, 1993-1994 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wells, Robert N., Jr., 1970 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wemple, Henry, 1957, 1977 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research, 1955-1991 (Box Series I-38)
    San Diego Museum of Man
  - Wenworth, Edward N., 1949 (Box Series I-38)
  - Weslager, C.A., 1941-1977 (Box Series I-38)
    Cooper, G. Arthur
    -See also Ser. I, Archaeological Society of Delaware
    -See also Ser. I, Deardorff, Merle H., 1946
  - West, Doris, 1949 (Box Series I-38)
  - West, Herbert Faulkner, 1953 (Box Series I-38)
    -See also Ser. I, Dartmouth College Library
  - Westez, Carlos, 1944-1958 (Box Series I-38)
  - West-Hill, James C., 1989 (Box Series I-38)
  - Weston, Harold (Box Series I-38)
    -See Ser. I, Fisher, Donald W.
  - Westport Town Crier & Herald, 1957 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wetmore, Alexander, 1949 (Box Series I-38)
    Martin, Edward
  - Wheatland, Stephen, 1949 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wheatley, Dennis, 1971 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wheeler, Paul F., 1964-1971, n.d. (Box Series I-38)
    -See also Ser. I, Ducey, Paul Richard
  - Whelan, Sidney S., Jr. (Box Series I-38)
    -See Ser. I, New York Community Trust
  - Whetzel, H.H., 1944 (Box Series I-38)
  - White, Clayton C., 1941-1944 (Box Series I-38)
  - White, Ethel H., 1977 (Box Series I-38)
  - White, Harry E., 1957 (Box Series I-38)
  - White, Lee C., 1961 (Box Series I-38)
  - White, Leslie A., 1944-1955, 1970 (Box Series I-38)
    -See also Ser. I, Cairns, Huntington
  - White, Marian E., 1969-1975 (Box Series I-38)
  - White, W. Bruce, 1985 (Box Series I-38)
  - Whitehill, Walter Muir, 1951 (Box Series I-38)
  - Alberty Whitman and Company, 1969 (Box Series I-38)
  - Whitney, Alvin G., 1950 (Box Series I-38)
  - Whitney, Gertrude Churchill, 1960-1962 (Box Series I-38)
  - Whittaker, David, 1971 (Box Series I-38)
  - Widmayer, Charles Edward, 1986 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wilcox, Ray, 1942 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wilcox-Gay Corporation, 1948 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wilder, Charles G., 1947 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wilder, David (Box Series I-38)
    -See Ser. I, Hamilton College Library
  - Wildoner, Dale E., 1946-1947 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wilkins, Leslie T., 1977 (Box Series I-38)
  - Willets, Jane, 1946-1947 (Box Series I-38)
  - William and Mary Quarterly, 1970 (Box Series I-38)
  - Williams, Basil, 1961 (Box Series I-38)
    -See also Ser. I, Kennedy, John F.
  - Williams, Edward F., 1949 (Box Series I-38)
  - Williams, Frederick W., 1947 (Box Series I-38)
  - Williams, Harry B., 1957 (Box Series I-38)
  - Williams, Hayden E., 1968 (Box Series I-38)
  - Williams, John S., Jr. (Box Series I-38)
  - Williams, Marianne, 1975 (Box Series I-38)
  - Williams, Paul, 1985-1986 (Box Series I-38)
  - Williams, R. Jerrel, 1965 (Box Series I-38)
  - Williams, Stephen, 1974 (Box Series I-38)
  - Willmott, Jill A., 1972 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wilson, Arthur, 1976 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wilson, Bernard E., 1947 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wilson, Claire M., 1993 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wilson, David, 1990, 1992 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wilson, Edmund, 1961, 1969 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wilson, Peter, 1976 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wilson, Rosalind Baker, 1991-1993 (Box Series I-38)
  - Winkel, Nina, 1977 (Box Series I-38)
    -See also Ser. I, Mochon, Donald
  - Wisbey, Herbert A., Jr., 1964, 1977 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wise, A.R.J., 1963 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wissler, Clark, 1935-1947 (Box Series I-38)
  - Witthoft, John, 1946-1954 (Box Series I-38)
  - WNYE, 1949 (Box Series I-38)
  - Wolf, Sam Gray, 1969 (Box Series I-39)
  - Wolf, Ted, 1990 (Box Series I-39)
  - Wolfe, William P., 1968 (Box Series I-39)
  - Wood, Blair, 1950, 199- (Box Series I-39)
  - Woodbury, Hanni J., 1976-1992 (Box Series I-39)
  - Woodbury, Nathalie F.S., 1986-1990 (Box Series I-39)
  - Woodbury, Richard B., 1982-1991 (Box Series I-39)
  - Woodland Cultural Centre, 1990 (Box Series I-39)
  - Woodside, M. St. A. (Box Series I-39)
    -See Ser. I, University of Toronto
  - Woodstock Press, 1942 (Box Series I-39)
  - Worl, Rosita, 1990 (Box Series I-39)
  - Wormington, H. Marie, 1961-1969 (Box Series I-39)
  - Wray, Charles, 1946, 1971-1972 (Box Series I-39)
  - Wray, Haltom, 1973-1974 (Box Series I-39)
  - Wright, Gordon K., 1959 (Box Series I-39)
  - Wright, Helen D., 1958 (Box Series I-39)
  - Wright, Jim V., 1965-1984 (Box Series I-39)
  - Wright, Ross Pier, 1939-1942 (Box Series I-39)
  - Wright, Roy, 1969 (Box Series I-39)
  - Wulff, Inger, 1963 (Box Series I-39)
  - Wuntch, David, 1949 (Box Series I-39)
  - Wykoff, M. William, 1972-1991 (Box Series I-39)
    Jamnback, Hugo
  - Wyman, Leland C., 1944-1946 (Box Series I-39)
  - Xerox Education Publications, 1976 (Box Series I-39)
  - Yale University, 1937 (Box Series I-39)
  - Yeager, Donald R., 1968 (Box Series I-39)
  - Young, Donald, 1947 (Box Series I-39)
  - Zahniser, Howard, 1946 (Box Series I-39)
    Lee, Alfred McClung
  - Zarzynski, Joseph W., 1976 (Box Series I-39)
  - Zelitch, Jeffrey, 1968 (Box Series I-39)
  - Zim, Sonia Bleeker, 1949-1950, 1967 (Box Series I-39)
  - Zimmerman, David, 1988 (Box Series I-39)
  - Zolotarevskaja, I.A. (Box Series I-39)
    -See Ser. I, Averkieva, Yu. P.
  - Zuidema, Tom, 1962 (Box Series I-39)
- Series IIa. Subject files, 1846-1992; 15 boxes; 7.5 linear feet
  Minutes, reports, agenda, conference abstracts, bulletins, legal documents, calendars, and newspaper clippings, arranged alphabetically by title. The earliest item in this series is a photocopy of an 1846 library catalog from the Thomas Indian School. The Museum of the American Indian files, which include minutes and agenda from the period when Fenton was an active board member, account for a significant portion of Series II. Fenton's reports on travel and work completed as a community worker for the U.S. Department of the Interior appear in this series as well. Of interest is the material on the construction of Kinzua Dam on the Allegheny River, and on the plans to establish Iroquoia, a tourist center to provide an historically accurate re-creation of an Iroquois community. Also of note are the wampum files which contain material on the ownership of numerous wampum belts at the Museum of the American Indian, the Rochester Museum and Science Center, and the New York State Museum. Copies of the title pages of reprints by and about Horatio Hale are filed under "Hale" in the series.
  - [Address Book], 1944 (Box Series IIa-1)
  - Akwesasne Mohawk Counselor Organization, n.d. (Box Series IIa-1)
  - Allegany and Cornplanter Indian negatives by Dorothy Skinner--List, 1928-1929 (Box Series IIa-1)
  - Allegany School of Natural History, 1938-1939 (Box Series IIa-1)
  - American Anthropological Association (Box Series IIa-1)
    -See also Ser. III, "Ethnology and Historiography"
    - Folder #1, 1935-1959 (Box Series IIa-1)
    - Folder #2, 1963-1965 (Box Series IIa-1)
    - Folder #3, 1966-1972 (Box Series IIa-1)
    - Folder #4, 1982-1983 (Box Series IIa-1)
  - American Association on Indian Affairs, Inc., 1942-1943, n.d. (Box Series IIa-1)
  - American Ethnohistorical Association, 1963 (Box Series IIa-1)
  - American Ethnological Society, 1957-1961 (Box Series IIa-1)
  - American Folklore Society, 1955-1959, 1979, n.d. (Box Series IIa-1)
  - American Indian Ethnohistoric Conference, 1963-1964 (Box Series IIa-1)
  - American Indian Heritage Committee, 1977 (Box Series IIa-1)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1967, 1970, 1983-1985 (Box Series IIa-1)
  - American Society for Ethnohistory, 1971, 1974, 1985-1989 (Box Series IIa-1)
  - "A Bibliography of Indian Captivities and Indian Related Materials from the Library of the Late Edna Greenwood of Marlborough, Massachusetts"--Ms. (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Bibliography--William N. Fenton, [1988] (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Biographical Material Re William N. Fenton, n.d. (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Calendars, 1937, 1949-1968, 1971 (Box Series IIa-2)
    26 vols. in 4 boxes; filed at end of Ser. IIa
  - Canadian Museum of Civilization, n.d. (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Cayuga County Historical Society, 1965-1971, 1979, 1986 (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Central States Anthropological Society, 1963 (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Champlain Society, 1976-1982, n.d. (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Cherokee-Iroquois Conference, 6-8 Apr. 1978 (Box Series IIa-2)
    -See also Ser. I, same title
    -See also Ser. III, "Cherokee and Iroquois Connections Revisited"
    -See also Ser. IV, Fogelson, Raymond D., "Major John Norton as Ethno-Ethnologist"
    -See also Ser. IV, Tooker, Elisabeth, "Some Reflections on Cherokee-Iroquois Culture-History"
  - Clippings, 1939-1986, n.d. (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Conference on Algonquian Research (1st), 1968 (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Conference on Iroquois Research, 1945-1966 (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Conference on Museums and Anthropology (Philadelphia), 1954 (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Cornplanter, Jesse J., 1903-1973, n.d. (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Cornplanter Medal, [1965] (Box Series IIa-2)
    -See also Ser. II, Cayuga County Historical Society
  - Council for Museum Anthropology, 1974-1976, n.d. (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Dartmouth College, 1977-1978 (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Merle H. Deardorff Collection, 1544-1971--Inventory, [1979] (Box Series IIa-2)
  - [Distribution List], 1946 (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Peter Doctor Memorial Indian Scholarship Foundation, 1962, 1987, n.d. (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Du Simitière Papers, 1982 (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Eastern Regional Conference on the Native American, 1980 (Box Series IIa-2)
  - The False Faces of the Iroquois--Reviews, 1987-1990, n.d. (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Glenbow Museum, 1985-1988, n.d. (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1974 (Box Series IIa-2)
  - Hale, Horatio E.--Reprints, 1881-1897, 1967, 1973 (Box Series IIa-3)
  - Human Relations Area Files, Inc., 1949 (Box Series IIa-3)
  - The Huntington, 1978-1979 (Box Series IIa-3)
  - The "Imperial" Iroquois--Conference on Early American History, 30-31 Mar. 1984 (Box Series IIa-3)
    -See also Ser. III, "Iroquois Political History: An Anthropological View"
  - Institute of Human Relations, 1934-1935 (Box Series IIa-3)
  - International Congress of Americanists (Cambridge, England), 1952 (Box Series IIa-3)
  - International Congress of Americanists (31st: Sao Paulo, Brazil), 1954 (Box Series IIa-3)
    -See also Ser. I, Baldus, Herbert
  - International Congress of Americanists (34th: Vienna), 1960 (Box Series IIa-3)
    -See also Ser. I, Heine-Geldern, Robert
    -See also Ser. I, Miranda, José
  - International Congress of Americanists (35th: Mexico City), 1962 (Box Series IIa-3)
  - International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences (3rd: Brussels), 1948 (Box Series IIa-3)
  - International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences (4th: Vienna), 1952 (Box Series IIa-3)
    -See also Ser. III, "Comment on an SOS of Ethnology"
    -See also Ser. III, "Factionalism in American Indian Society"
    -See also Ser. VI, International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences (4th: Vienna) 1952
  - International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences (5th: Philadelphia), 1954-1956 (Box Series IIa-3)
    -See also Ser. I, Finch, Glenn
    -See also Ser. I, Kluckhohn, Clyde
    -See also Ser. I, Meyriat, J.
    -See also Ser. I, Rainey, Froelich
    -See also Ser. I, Smith, L.G.
  - International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences (6th: Paris), 1960 (Box Series IIa-3)
  - International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences (7th: Moscow), 1964 (Box Series IIa-3)
    -See also Ser. I, Debetz, G.F.
    -See also Ser. I, Hochschild, Harold
    -See also Ser. I, Social Science Research Council
    -See also Ser. I, Tolstov, S.P.
    -See also Ser. VI, International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences (7th: Moscow) 1964
  - International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences (8th: Tokyo), 1968 (Box Series IIa-3)
  - International Council of Museums, 1962 (Box Series IIa-3)
  - International Union of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences, 1956-1973, n.d. (Box Series IIa-3)
    -See also Ser. I, Embassy of the Czechoslovak Socialist Republic
    -See also Ser. I, Herskovitz, Melville
    -See also Ser. I, Horák, Jiri
  - Iroquoia (Box Series IIa-3)
    - Folder #1, 1963-1965 (Box Series IIa-3)
    - Folder #2, 1965 (Box Series IIa-4)
    - Folder #3, 1965-1966, n.d. (Box Series IIa-4)
  - "The Iroquois in American Letters: Carl Carmer, Walter Edmonds, and Edmund Wilson", [1980] (Box Series IIa-4)
  - "Kin and Communities: The Peopling of America"--Smithsonian Symposium, 14-17 Jun. 1977 (Box Series IIa-4)
    -See also Ser. I, Fried, Morton H.
    -See also Ser. III, "Morgan's Legacy to Iroquois Studies and to American Ethnology"
  - Kinzua Dam (Box Series IIa-4)
    -See also Ser. I, Abbett, Robert
    -See also Ser. I, Bower, Blair T.
    -See also Ser. I, Cassidy, William
    -See also Ser. I, Elsbree, Hugh L.
    -See also Ser. I, Freeman, Norman
    -See also Ser. I, Haines, Robert
    -See also Ser. I, Haley, James
    -See also Ser. I, Itschner, Emerson
    -See also Ser. I, Morgan, Arthur
    -See also Ser. I, Morgan, Ernest
    -See also Ser. I, O'Neill, Edward
    -See also Ser. I, Ostertag, Harold
    -See also Ser. I, Robbins, Clyde
    -See also Ser. I, Seneca, Cornelius
    -See also Ser. I, United States. Department of Agriculture
    -See also Ser. I, White, Lee C.
    -See also Ser. III, [Pickering Treaty]--Ms.
    -See also Ser. VI, Kinzua Dam
    - Folder #1, 1951-1957 (Box Series IIa-4)
    - Folder #2, 1957-1958 (Box Series IIa-4)
    - Folder #3, 1958-1959 (Box Series IIa-4)
    - Folder #4, 1959-1964 (Box Series IIa-4)
    - Folder #5, 1964 (Box Series IIa-4)
    - Folder #6, 1964 (Box Series IIa-5)
    - Folder #7, 1964-1966 (Box Series IIa-5)
    - Folder #8, n.d. (Box Series IIa-5)
    - Folder #9--Clippings, 1939-1962 (Box Series IIa-5)
    - Folder #10--Clippings, 1963-1965, n.d. (Box Series IIa-5)
  - Lafitau, Joseph-François, 1960, 1989 (Box Series IIa-5)
    -See also Ser. III, "Customs of the American Indians...Lafitau"
  - Library of Congress, 1953, n.d. (Box Series IIa-5)
  - London, 1952, 1964 (Box Series IIa-5)
  - Louisiana State University Press, 1968-1969, 1975-1978 (Box Series IIa-5)
  - Maps, 1967, 1969 (Box Series IIa-5)
  - Medicine. Sample Sold by Betsy Chrisjohn General Antone to Cure Ulcers Internal and External, 28 Feb. 1973 (Box Series IIa-5)
  - Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation. Annual Reports (Box Series IIa-5)
    - Folder #1, 1973-1980 (Box Series IIa-5)
    - Folder #2, 1983-1988 (Box Series IIa-5)
  - Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation. Board of Trustees. Minutes (Box Series IIa-6)
    - Folder #1, 1976-May 1977 (Box Series IIa-6)
    - Folder #2, Jun. 1977-Jan. 1978 (Box Series IIa-6)
    - Folder #3, Mar.-Sep. 1978 (Box Series IIa-6)
    - Folder #4, Sep. 1978-May 1979 (Box Series IIa-6)
    - Folder #5, Sep. 1979-Mar. 1980 (Box Series IIa-6)
    - Folder #6, Jul. 1980-Sep. 1981 (Box Series IIa-7)
    - Folder #7, Jan. 1982-1983 (Box Series IIa-7)
    - Folder #8, 1984-May 1985 (Box Series IIa-7)
    - Folder #9, Jun. 1985-1986 (Box Series IIa-7)
    - Folder #10, May 1987-Sep. 1987 (Box Series IIa-7)
    - Folder #11, Dec. 1987-Mar. 1988 (Box Series IIa-8)
    - Folder #12, May-Dec 1988 (Box Series IIa-8)
    - Folder #13, 1989 (Box Series IIa-8)
  - Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation. Charter, 1930, 1976 (Box Series IIa-8)
  - Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation. Clippings (Box Series IIa-8)
    - Folder #1, 1985-1987 (Box Series IIa-8)
    - Folder #2, 1988-1989 (Box Series IIa-8)
  - Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation. Collections Policy, 1978, 1982 (Box Series IIa-8)
  - Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation. Comprehensive Plan, 1985-1986 (Box Series IIa-8)
    -See also oversized
  - Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation. Constitution and By-Laws, 1973, 1976, 1980 (Box Series IIa-9)
  - Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation. Curatorial Council. Minutes (Box Series IIa-9)
    - Folder #1, 1980-1983 (Box Series IIa-9)
    - Folder #2, 1984-1988 (Box Series IIa-9)
  - Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation. Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees. Minutes, 1978, 1981, 1985-1989 (Box Series IIa-9)
  - Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation. Miscellaneous, 1949, 1976, 1980 (Box Series IIa-9)
  - Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation. National Council for the Museum, 1980-1981, n.d. (Box Series IIa-9)
  - Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation. Nominating Committee, 1979 (Box Series IIa-9)
    -See also Ser. I, Des Grange, Jane
    -See also Ser. I, Dorris, Michael
    -See also Ser. II, Museum of the American Indian...Board of Trustees. Minutes
  - Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation. Publications Committee, 1979-1980 (Box Series IIa-9)
  - Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation. Task Force Committee (Box Series IIa-9)
    - Folder #1, 1976-Jun. 1977 (Box Series IIa-9)
    - Folder #2, Jul.-Aug. 1977 (Box Series IIa-9)
  - Museum of the Plains Indian, 1942, n.d. (Box Series IIa-9)
  - National Museum of Canada, 1967 (Box Series IIa-9)
  - National Museum of Man, 1983 (Box Series IIa-9)
  - National Research Council. Committee on International Cooperation in Anthropology, 1945-1955, 1965 (Box Series IIa-10)
    -See also Ser. I, Herskovits, Melville
    -See also Ser. I, National Research Council
  - Negatives, 1933-1951 (Box Series IIa-10)
    -See also Ser. IIa, Photograph Descriptions
  - Newberry Library, 1983-1988 (Box Series IIa-10)
  - Northeastern Anthropological Association, 1968, 1970-1971 (Box Series IIa-10)
  - Photograph Descriptions, 1958 (Box Series IIa-10)
  - "Problems Arising from the Historic Northeastern Position of the Iroquois"--Review, 1941 (Box Series IIa-10)
  - Resources for the Future, Inc., 1973-1974 (Box Series IIa-10)
  - "Return to the Longhouse"--Reviews, 1972 (Box Series IIa-10)
  - Rochester Museum and Science Center, 1979, 1983, 1985-1986 (Box Series IIa-10)
  - Rochester Museum of Arts and Sciences, 1956 (Box Series IIa-10)
  - Sapir Centenary Conference, 1984-1987, n.d. (Box Series IIa-10)
    -See also Ser. I, Preston, Richard J.
    -See also Ser. I, Sapir, Philip
  - Schuyler Papers, n.d. (Box Series IIa-10)
  - Seneca Nation of Indians, 1985 (Box Series IIa-10)
  - "Seth Newhouse's Traditional History and Constitution of the Iroquois Confederacy", 1949 (Box Series IIa-10)
    -See also Ser. I, Drummond, Richard C.S., 1949
    -See also Ser. I, Randle, E.P., 1948
    -See also Ser. III, "Seth Newhouse's Constitution of the Iroquois Confederacy"
  - Six Nations Association, 1935, 1969 (Box Series IIa-10)
  - Smithsonian Institution, [1939-1951] (Box Series IIa-10)
  - Society for American Archaeology, 1947 (Box Series IIa-10)
  - Society of Washington Artists, 1945 (Box Series IIa-10)
  - Southwestern Anthropological Association, 1979 (Box Series IIa-10)
  - Thomas Indian School, 1846, 1949, 1955 (Box Series IIa-10)
  - Tonawanda Indian Reservation Community Association, 1937, 1939 (Box Series IIa-10)
  - Triptik, 1940 (Box Series IIa-10)
  - United States. Bureau of Placement, n.d. (Box Series IIa-10)
  - United States. Department of the Interior, 1934-1938, n.d. (Box Series IIa-10)
  - United States. Naval Reserve, 1942-1943, n.d. (Box Series IIa-11)
  - Wampum. Miscellanea, 1886-1970 (Box Series IIa-11)
  - Wampum. Museum of the American Indian (Box Series IIa-11)
    -See also Ser. VI, "Six Nations Indian Chiefs of the Iroquois Confederacy"
    -See also Ser. VI, Wampum. Museum of the American Indian
    -See also Ser. VI, Wampum Transfer. Museum of the American Indian
    - Folder #1, 1870-1992, n.d. (Box Series IIa-11)
    - Folder #2, n.d. (Box Series IIa-11)
    - Folder #3, n.d. (Box Series IIa-11)
  - Wampum. New York State Museum (Box Series IIa-11)
    -See also Ser. I, Abrams, George
    -See also Ser. I, Bishop, Charles
    -See also Ser. I, Broughton, John
    -See also Ser. I, Gillette, Charles
    -See also Ser. I, Indian Historian
    -See also Ser. I, Lafayette Teachers Association
    -See also Ser. I, Mele, Bette Crouse
    -See also Ser. I, Plummer, Genevieve
    -See also Ser. I, Powless, Irving, Jr.
    -See also Ser. I, Prucha, John James
    -See also Ser. I, Reilly, Joseph M.
    -See also Ser. I, Rockefeller, Nelson
    -See also Ser. I, Syracuse Herald-Journal
    -See also Ser. I, Tolman, Mason
    -See also Ser. I, Wagner, Waltraud
    -See also Ser. I, Wray, Charles
    - Folder #1, 1872-1964 (Box Series IIa-11)
    - Folder #2, 1967-1989, n.d. (Box Series IIa-11)
  - Wampum. Rochester Museum and Science Center (Box Series IIa-11)
  - Yale University, 1934-1935 (Box Series IIa-11)
- Series IIb. Iroquois Documentary History Project, 1635-1989; 3 boxes; 1.5 linear feet
  Material gathered during a project undertaken by the Newberry Library to compile a documentary history of the Iroquois. Involved in the project were Fenton, Francis P. Jennings, and Mary A. Druke Becker, among others. This series contains material that was compiled by the project, including photocopies of historical documents, such as treaties, deeds, and minutes of meetings with Iroquois leaders. There are two folders of project reports ("Iroquois Documentary History Project Reports") written by Becker, Fenton, and Jennings. Correspondence involving this project has been filed in Series I, in the files of Becker and Jennings.
  - "An Account of the First Confederacy of the Six Nations..." from The American Magazine, Dec. 1744 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Albany. Treaty at, 1722 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Ancaster. Council Held with Six Nations Indians--Minutes, 26-28 Mar. 1819 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Archives du Seminaire de Quebec, n.d. (Box Series IIb-1)
  - "A Cayuga League Tradition"--Collected by J.N.B. Hewitt from Abram Charles. Revised by John Buck, Jr., 1917 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Condolence (Box Series IIb-1)
    -See Oversized
  - Covenant Chain (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Deeds, 1672-1784 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - "Dehadodahho?"--J.N.B. Hewitt from Joshua Buck, 1917 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Desrosiers, Léo-Paul. Writings (Box Series IIb-1)
    - Folder #1, 1945-1956 (Box Series IIb-1)
    - Folder #2, 1957-1962 (Box Series IIb-1)
    - Folder #3, 1963-1966 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Duane, James. List of Treaties and Acts of New York over Territory of the Five Nations, 1870 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Dutch Journal to Mohawk Country, 1635 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Fort Stanwix. Affirmation of 3 Nov. 1768 Deed of Six Nations to Pennsylvania at, 1769 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Fort Stanwix. Treaty at, 1784 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Handsome Lake's Passport--In the Huntingon, 1802 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - J.N.B. Hewitt Library. Unidentified Text, 1930 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Historical Text--Collected by J.N.B. Hewitt from Baptist Thomas, 1889 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Iroquois Documentary History Project Reports (Box Series IIb-1)
    -See also Ser. I, Huntington Free Library and Reading Room
    -See also Ser. I, Lancaster County Library
    -See also Ser. I, Miller, David R.
    - Folder #1, 1978-Aug. 1980 (Box Series IIb-1)
    - Folder #2, Sep. 1980-1981, n.d. (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Iroquois Politics, References to. In Schuyler Papers, New York Public Library, 1710-1795 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Iroquois Treaties in National Archives, 1978 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Johnson, Guy, 1771-1777 (Box Series IIb-1)
  - Johnson, William, 1771-1772 (Box Series IIb-1)